Guide to the Laura Gray Political Cartoons GRAPHICS.013
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Laura Gray Political Cartoons
1944-1957
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Gray, Laura
Slobe, Laura, 1909-1958
Lovell, Frank
GRAPHICS.013
10.5 Linear Feet in 6 oversized flat boxes, 2 record cartons, and 1 folder in shared housing
Laura Gray (also known as Laura Slobe), born in 1909 in Pittsburgh, was a sculptor, painter, and a staff artist for the Socialist Workers Party newspaper The Militant, producing weekly political cartoons for the publication from 1944 until her death in 1958. Gray used a large format for her work and was particularly effective in effective in capturing political personalities and sharply analyzing both national and international issues, particularly those that affected workers. The Laura Gray Political Cartoons collection consists of over 500 original Laura Gray cartoons covering nearly the entire time Gray worked for The Militant. The medium used was a waxy crayon on paper. The collection also contains nine binders with reference copies of a majority of the cartoons. Several themes run through the cartoons, including anti-communism, the economy, racism, Jim Crow legislation, the Korean War, labor, political parties, and depictions of US presidents Roosevelt, Truman, and Eisenhower. The collection also includes a run of Gray's "Rich Bitch" series, which features caricatures of a stereotyped wealthy woman.
Scope and Contents
The Laura Gray Political Cartoons consists of just under 600 original drawings that Gray produced for the Socialist Workers Party paper The Militant.. The drawings cover nearly the whole of Gray's career at The Militant, and span the years 1944-1957. The drawings are generally large format, waxy crayon on paper. They depict the major issues of the time, including the end of World War II, the rise of McCarthyism, and the Korean War, as well as current events and newsstories. Additionally, Gray's drawings portray political and labor figures of the day, including Presidents Roosevelt, Truman, and Eisenhower and labor leaders including Sidney Hillman, George Meany, and Philip Murray. The collection also includes nine reference binders that contain photocopies of 512 of the drawings, and a run of Gray's "Rich Bitch" series, which features caricatures of a stereotyped wealthy woman.
Biographical Note
Laura Gray was born Laura Slobe, in Pittsburgh in 1909, to a prosperous Jewish family, but she grew up in Chicago. At age 16, she enrolled at the Art Institute of Chicago. By 19, she began exhibiting paintings, winning a number of prizes, and her paintings continued to appear in exhibits at the Institute and in several galleries. By the late 1930s, she began to produce and exhibit avant-garde sculpture as well, and eventually became known more for her sculpture than her painting. Her work continued to be shown in exhibits in the Chicago area until 1944.
From spring 1939 through September 1940, Gray worked for the Illinois division of the federal Works Progress Administration's Painting and Sculptures Section, creating works of art for the program, as well as serving as an art instructor for it in Illinois and in several other states, traveling as far afield as Oregon. Gray became friendly with a group of other Chicago avante-garde artists attracted by Troskyism. One of the group was George Perle (born George Perlstein, 1915-2009), a composer, whom she married in 1940. (In the 1960s Perle became a major theorist of serialism--a method of composition associated with Schoenberg's 12-tone technique—and was awarded a Pulitizer Prize and a MacArthur fellowship in 1986.)
In 1942 Gray and Perle joined the Trotskyist organization, the Socialist Workers Party (SWP), in Chicago. Not long after joining the SWP Laura Slobe took the name "Laura Gray," a "party name" (a pseudonym adopted by a member of a political party to hide his or her real identity to avoid political, legal or workplace persecution, surveillance and discrimination). Within a few weeks, she was assigned by the SWP to assist with organizing workers in the automobile industry, and she employed her artistic skills by drawing cartoons for a union shop paper. The SWP's branch organizer recognized her skill and encouraged her to submit a cartoon to the SWP's newspaper, The Militant. Gray's first cartoon in The Militant appeared on March 4, 1944, and thereafter at least one of her cartoons appeared (under the name "Laura Gray") in The Militant almost weekly for the rest of her life, and she became the paper's staff artist. Many of Gray's cartoons published in The Militant were also reproduced in Trotskyist and Trotskyist-associated labor publications in as many as 20 countries. While many praised her work as a graphic artist—one scholar describing her cartoons as "naturalistic and powerful, in the tradition of The Masses' Boardman Robinson, and warrant[ing] comparison to artists such as Hugo Gellert and Robert Minor," Gray herself did not consider her cartoons to be serious art; she remained devoted to sculpture and painting.
Gray and Perle moved to New York City soon after World War II. They were legally divorced in 1952, but remained close friends. In the late 1940s and early 1950s she lived on and off with Duncan Ferguson (1901-74), a sculptor and fellow SWP member. Evidently her work for The Militant was not enough to support Gray; she also worked simultaneously at a number of temporary jobs, including painting mannequins and creating window display art for department stores. As the years went by she devoted less and less of her time to her own art as a sculptor and painter, although she longed to return to it. Gray's health was fragile; she had suffered from tuberculosis in her early twenties, and had had a lung removed in 1947. She died in 1958, at the age of 49, when she contracted pneumonia that rapidly turned fatal. A prize in sculpture was established in her name at the Art Institute of Chicago, and a George Perle composed a quintet for strings titled "In Memory of Laura Slobe."
Gray used a large format for her cartoons. She was particularly effective in capturing political personalities (including U.S. Presidents Roosevelt, Truman, and Eisenhower) and sharply analyzing both national and international issues, particularly those that affected workers. Her subjects (chosen by The Militant's editorial committee) include racism (especially the Emmett Till case, Jim Crow legislation, the poll tax, and the Ku Klux Klan), labor and unemployment, and mainstream U.S. political parties. During World War II, subjects of satire included the War Labor Board, the no-strike pledge, and the Little Steel Formula; postwar the Marshall Plan, the Korean War, the red scare of the 1950s, and the United States government's embrace of dictators such as Spain's Francisco Franco, were included among her targets.
Related Archival Material
George Breitman Papers (TAM 169)
Frank Lovell Papers (TAM 204)
Socialist Workers Party Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 027)
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions. Researchers are requested to use the complete set of photocopies (arranged in chronological order in binders) for reference whenever possible, in order to preserve the original materials.
Custodial History
The cartoons were originally prepared for The Militant by Laura Gray as part of her staff duties. The cartoons were held by George Weissman until his death. The collection was donated to the Tamiment Library in 1988 by Frank Lovell.
Arrangement
The Laura Gray Political Cartoons are arranged in two series: I. Cartoons and II. Reference Binders. The cartoons are arranged alphabetically by subject and the reference binders are arranged chronologically.
Missing Title
1. Cartoons
II. Reference Binders
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Users are requested to use the complete set of photocopies (arranged in chronological order in binders) for reference whenever possible, to preserve the original materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Frank Lovell, 1988. The accession number associated with this gift is 1988.015.
The accession number NPA.2000.337 is also associated with this collection.
In July 2023, one cartoon depicting meatpacking bosses was donated by The Anchor Foundation; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.081.
Bibliography
Biographical information for this guide was mainly drawn from the following sources: Alan Wald, "Cannonite Bohemians After World War II." Against the Current, July/August 2012, pp. 25-35 (and PDF of extended edition on the Web: http://www.solidarity-us.org/pdfs/ATC%20159--Wald.pdf ) and Kent Worchester, "Sculptor, Painter, and Cartoonist: Laura Gray." New Politics, Summer 2013, pp. 159-163.
Cartoonists -- United States; Caricatures and cartoons.; Communism -- United States.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States.; Lynching.; Wages.; Korean War, 1950-1953; Civil rights.; Labor leaders -- United States.; Labor laws and legislation -- United States.; Labor -- United States.; Labor unions -- Elections.; Unemployment |z United States.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Socialist Workers Party; United States. Labor Management Relations Act, 1947; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972; Stalin, Joseph, 1878-1953; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; Perle, George, 1915-; Federal Art Project; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965; Lovell, Frank
- Series I: Cartoons
  Scope and Content Note
  Contains over 600 original cartoons produced by Laura Gray while she worked for the Socialist Workers Party's paper, the Militant. The drawings are large format, waxy crayon on paper. Several themes run through the cartoons, surfacing throughout. These include anti-communism, depictions of US presidents Roosevelt, Truman, and Eisenhower, the economy, Jim Crow, the Korean War, labor, political parties, as well as a run of Gray's "Rich Bitch" series.
  - Algeria, March 18, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism, Jan 1956, Jan 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Communism: Civil Liberties, Apr-Jul, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism: Clark, Tom, Aug 8, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism: Dies Committee, Jan 13, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Communism: Kutcher, James, Sep 1948-Jul 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism: Labor, Sep 13, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism: Loyalty Oaths, Jun 1949-Jul 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism: March, Fredric, Jun 20, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Communism: McCarthyism, Sep 1952-Aug 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 5, Box 2, Folder 3, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism: Military, Aug 15, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Communism: Nixon, Sep 29, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism: NY Teachers, Mar 7, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Communism: Rosenbergs, Jun 1950-Jun 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3, Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Communism: Witch-Hunts, May 28, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arms Race, Oct-Dec 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Asia, Oct 30, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Asia: MacArthur, 1Sep 11, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy, Apr 1946-Apr 1950, undated (Flat-file-folder 5, Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Atomic Energy: A-Bomb, Oct 17, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy: Eisenhower, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Atomic Energy: Eisenhower/Dulles, Aug 31, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy: H-Bomb, Feb 1950-Jul 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Atomic Energy: Nuclear Testing, Jun-Aug 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Belgium: Pierlot, Dec 9, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bill of Rights, undated (Box 6, Folder 6, Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bolivia, Nov 10, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book Burning, Jul 6, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bulganin, Nikolai, Jul 25, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cardinal Spellman, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - China: Eisenhower/Dulles, Aug 10, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cicero Indictments, Oct 1, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Civil Rights, Aug 19, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights: Democrats/Republicans, Nov 7, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights: Eisenhower, Feb 11, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights: Voting, Dec 5, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Communist Party USA, May 1944-Jan 1949 (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Congress, Apr 3, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Congress: Hatch-Burton-Ball Bill, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Congress: Little Steel Formula, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Congress: Prices, Jul 23, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Corruption: Labor, Oct 9, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Counter Revolution, undated (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Dulles, John Foster, May 25, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economy, Aug 24, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Economy: Baruch Plan, Mar 4, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economy: Budget, Jan 1949-Jan 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economy: Capitalism, Dec 27, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economy: Jobs, Feb 28, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economy: Plant Runway, Nov 8, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economy: Profits/Welfare State, Mar 27, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Economy: Recession, Jan 18, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Economy: Wages, Feb 1949-Mar 1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Economy: Wall Street, Jun-Jul 1946 (Flat-file-folder 5, Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Egypt: Suez War, Aug 13, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Eisenhower, Dec 1952-Oct 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6, Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: Cabinet, Dec 1, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower: Campaign, Jan-Aug 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6, Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: Chiang Kai-Shek, Feb 16, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: Civilian Defense, Jun 17, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: Drug Manufacturers/Polio Vaccine, May 30, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: Economy, Feb 8, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eisenhower: International Relations, Jan 15, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower: War, Jan 19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: Hoover, J. Edgar, Jan 1950-Mar 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: KKK, Jan 7, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - France, Aug 25, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - France: Govin, Felix, Feb 23, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - France: Thorez, Maurice, Jan 4, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Franco, Jul 1951-Oct 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Franco: Congress, Sep 4, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Germany: Post-WWII, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Germany: Rearmament, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Germany: Worker's Revolt, Jul 13, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Great Britain: Churchill, Jun 2, 1945, undated (Box 6, Folder 8, Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Great Britain: Labor, Aug 4, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greece, Mar 22, 1947 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Greece:Churchill, Jan 20, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Guatemala: United Fruit Company, Jun-Jul 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13, Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hungary: General Strike, Nov 26, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Indochina, Oct-Nov 1945, undated (Box 6, Folder 9, Box 5, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Indochina: Marshall Plan, Jan 3, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Iran: Oil, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Italy, Jan-Jul 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Italy: Roosevelt, President Franklin Delano, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, President Andrew, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Japan: Japanese Peace Act, Sep 17, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Japan: Labor, Aug 9, 1948 (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Jim Crow, Jun 1950, May 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jim Crow: Bus Boycott, Feb 13, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jim Crow: KKK, Feb 18, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jim Crow: Stevenson, Adlai, Feb 27, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jury Room, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Khrushchev, Nikita, Jun 6, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - King Michael, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Korean War, Jul 1950-Jun 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10, Folder 9, Box 2, Folder 15, Box 3, Folder 1, Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Korean War: Censorship, Jan-Oct 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Korean War: Christmas, Dec 25, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Korean War: Eisenhower, Dec 1952-Apr 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9, Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Korean War: Eisenhower/Dulles, Aug 17, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Korean War: Eisenhower/Stevenson, Oct 13, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Korean War: MacArthur, Apr 30, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Korean War: Socialist Workers Party, Oct 27, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Korean War: Truman, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Labor, Feb 1945-May 1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 15, Flat-file-folder 2, Box 6, Folder 6, Box 5, Folder 8-9)
  - Labor: AFL-CIO, Apr 21, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Anti-Labor Laws, Jan-Mar 1947, undated (Flat-file-folder 5, Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Labor: Automation, Dec 13, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Labor: Autoworkers, Dec 1945, Sep 1957 (Box 6, Folder 12, Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Labor: Beck, Dave, Oct 1953, Apr 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Labor: Big Business, Apr 8, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Labor: Case Bill, Jun 22, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Democratic Party, Nov 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Labor: Fair Deal, Nov 1, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Labor: Fair Employment Practices Commission, Jul 1945-May1950 (Flat-file-folder 5, Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Labor: Food, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Hillman, Sydney, Dec 30, 1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 8, Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Labor: International Solidarity, Apr 24, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Labor: KKK, undated (Box 3, Folder 8, Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Labor: Labor Leaders, Apr 1945-Sep 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor: Lay-offs, May 12, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Labor: Lewis, John L., undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Little Steel Formula, May 13, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor: May Day, Apr 26, 1947 (Flat-file-folder 1, Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Meany, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Meatpacking Bosses, circa 1909-1958 (Box Shared Tamiment 196, Folder 3)
  - Labor: Miners, May 1946-Mar 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4, Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Labor: Murray, Phillip, Nov 1949-Dec 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Labor: New York Dodgers, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Labor: No Strike Pledge, Jun 30, 1945, undated (Flat-file-folder 5, Box 6, Folder 12, Folder 10)
  - Labor: Profits, Dec 3, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor: Railroad Workers, Feb-Apr 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor: Reuther, Walter, Mar 12, 1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Labor: Soldiers (unity), Jan 12, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Labor: Steel, Sep-Oct 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5, Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Labor: Strike Breakers, Mar 14, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws, Mar 1945-Aug 1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 6, Flat-file-folder 1, Box 6, Folder 11-12, Box 5, Folder 5, Flat-file-folder 2, Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws (GM), Dec 1945-Mar 1946 (Box 5, Folder 6, Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws (Miners), Nov 1946-Apr 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7, Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws (Steel), Jul 14, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws (Taft-Hartley), Dec 1948-Dec 1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 6, Box 5, Folder 7, Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Labor: Strikes, Strike Laws (UAW), Oct 24, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Labor: Textiles, Mar 3, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Labor: Unemployment, Jun 1945-Dec 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 7, Box 1, Folder 14, Box 5, Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Labor: Unity, Jun-Dec 1946 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Labor: Wage Freeze, Mar 1945-Jul 1951 (Box 6, Folder 10, Box 5, Folder 7, Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Labor: Wage Stabilization Board, Feb 1951-Feb 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Labor: Wages, undated (Flat-file-folder 2, Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Labor: Wages/Unemployment, Jan 16, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Labor: Workers of the World Unite, Apr 28, 1945 (Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Latin America, May 18, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Liberation Struggles, Dec 1956-Apr 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lynching, Aug 1946-Jan 1952 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lynching: Eastland, Mar 1956-Jan 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lynching: Post-WWII, Sep 28, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Malenkov, Georgy, Mar 16, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mao Tsetung, Apr 25, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - McCarran-Kilgore Bill, Sep 25, 1950 (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - McCarthy, Joseph, May 18, 1953, undated (Box 1, Folder 11, Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Meat Trust, Mar 1945-May 1951 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Militant (25th Anniversary), Nov 9, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Military, Sep 24, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Military: West Point, Aug 13, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Montgomery: Carpool, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mundt Bill, May 1948, Mar 1950 (Flat-file-folder 2, Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NAACP: Derrick, John, Mar 5, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Oil Scandal: Ickes, Feb 23, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Peace Time Conscription, Nov 1945-Mar 1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Peace Time Conscription: Wall Street, Jun 23, 1945 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Photostats, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Police, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Political Parties, Nov 1946-Sep 1948 (Flat-file-folder 2, Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Political Parties: Big Business, Oct 21, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: Bill of Rights, Aug-Oct 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Political Parties: Campaign Promises, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Political Parties: Democrats, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: Democrats/Republicans, Nov 1950-Oct 1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 18, Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: Eisenhower/Stevenson, Oct 6, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: Kefauver, Estes, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: KKK, Aug 18, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Political Parties: Labor, Oct 1950, May 1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 8, Box 3, Folder 11, Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Political Parties: Labor Party, Apr 1951-Apr 1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 7, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 2, Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Political Parties: Marshall, Oct 18, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Political Parties: Socialist Workers Party, Nov 1944-Oct 1956, undated (Box 5, Folder 11, Flat-file-folder 2, Box 6, Folder 5, Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Political Parties: Special Session, Jul-Aug 1948 (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Political Parties: Wallace, Jun-Oct 1948 (Flat-file-folder 2, Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Political Prisoners, Jun 10, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Political Prisoners: Trenton Two, Jun 25, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Poll Tax, May 6, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Post-WWII, Feb-Jul 1945, undated (Flat-file-folder 1, Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Post-WWII: Big Three Unity, May 25, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Post-WWII: Big Three Unity, May 25, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Post-WWII: Jewish Refugees, Aug 24, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Post-WWII: Unemployment, May 1945 (Box 3, Folder 12, Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Post-WWII: United Nations, Jul 7, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Post-WWII: Wages, Oct 14, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Post-WWII: Yalta, Feb 17, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Puerto Rico, Nov 13, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rearmament, Apr 7, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rent, Nov 1946-Jun 1950 (Flat-file-folder 1, Box 5, Folder 3, Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rich Bitch Series, Mar 1945-Apr 1947, undated (Flat-file-folder 1, Box 4, Folder 1-11)
  - Roosevelt, President Franklin Delano, Dec 1944-Mar 1945 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Roosevelt, President Franklin Delano: Montgomery Ward, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - School Segregation, Oct 1954-Oct 1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 1)
  - School Segregation: Little Rock, Sep 16, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Smith Act, Aug 2, 1948 (Flat-file-folder 2)
  - Socialist Education: Eastland, Jun 3, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Stalin, Joseph, Mar 1953-Jul 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)